Finding Aid for Clara Hadley Wait papers, 1893-1919
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Clara Hadley Wait papers 1893-1919
Wait, Clara Hadley
16 volumes (in 1 box)
86189 Aa 2
Member of the Michigan Daughters of the American Revolution; scrapbooks, journals, and photograph albums.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Rolland C. Stewart (donor no. 2446 ) and came to the library in 1949.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Clara H. Waite was state regent of the Michigan Daughters of the American Revolution. She and her husband William H. Wait, a professor of German and other modern languages at the University of Michigan traveled extensively and were engaged in the social life of Ann Arbor.
The Clara Hadley Wait collection includes scrapbooks, notebooks on art, travel journals, DAR materials, and photograph albums. The scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, correspondence, copies of her articles, and other materials relating primarily to her civic activities, including description of her activities with the D.A.R. during World War I. The collection includes a European travel diary, 1893, of her husband, William H. Wait.
Subjects:
Daughters of the American Revolution.; Europe--Description and travel.; Patriotic societies--Michigan.; Voyages and travels.; Women--Michigan--Societies and clubs.; World War, 1914-1918.; Wait, Clara Hadley.
Contributors:
Wait, William H. (William Henry)
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks:
  - "William H. and Clara H. Wait and Their Doings in Illinois," 1883-1895 (Box 1)
  - "William H. and Clara H. Wait and Some of their doings," 1895-1925 (Box 1)
  - "Clara H. Wait and Some of Her Doings in Michigan," 1895-1914 (Box 1)
  - Clara H Wait, 1915-1925 (Box 1)
- Notebooks:
  - "History of Art" notes, Berlin, 1893, 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - "Description of Paintings", Berlin, 1893 (Box 1)
  - "Painting", Berlin, 1893 (Box 1)
  - "German Literature notes", 1893 (Box 1)
- Journals:
  - European Travel, 1893-1894, 2 volumes (Box 1)
    (includes entries on Venice, Naples, Milan, Paris, Germany, and other places)
  - William Wait European Journal, 1893-1894 (Box 1)
- Daughters of the American Revolution Volumes:
  - "Report and Data of Sixth State Regent", 1916 (Box 1)
    (includes 14 page biography of Clara Wait)
  - "Appeals and Bulletins 1915-1919" (Box 1)
    (Includes correspondence, clippings, and articles by Clara Wait)
- Photo Albums:
  - Trip to Cascade, Colorado, summer 1900 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified Albums, undated (Box 1)
    (primarily photos of people riding or learning to ride horses/donkeys)